Finding Aid for the John Allison Benjamin Papers Biomed.0001
UCLA Library Special Collections
- IV. SUPPORTING RESEARCH MATERIALS
  - IV. B. MATERIALS ON MEDICINE & MEDICAL EDUCATION
    - International Symposium on the History of Medical Education, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 17)
      letter from C.D. O'Malley to JAB announcing plan for the symposium, to honor JAB's gift of his book collection to the UCLA Biomedical Library; program of the symposium which was supported by the Josiah Macy, Jr. Foundation, Feb. 1968
    - Reprints: current science & medicine except genito-urinary system, 1933-1987 (Box 5, Folder 18)
      includes Jan. 1935 issue of the Danziger Ärzteblatt; three reprints by Ernst Scharrer, 1932-1935; and others
    - Reprints, photostats, brochures: history of medicine, 1935-1976 (Box 5, Folder 19)
      by various authors, some with author inscription; brochure on physician contributions to the American Revolution; facsimile of pp. 193-204 of The Grounds of Physick, by John Greenfield, 1715; photostat of Bozzini's original publication on the Lichtleiter; photos & negatives of Bozzini material; correspondence
    - Reprints, photostats, brochures: history of medical education, 1966-1984 (Box 5, Folder 20)
      for items concerning Johns Hopkins, UCLA & Rochester medical schools, see Box 5-F21, F22 & F23, respectively
    - Reprints, brochures, correspondence: history of TheJohns Hopkins School of Medicine, 1933-1985 (Box 5, Folder 21)
      "Report of the dean of the Medical Faculty, 1933-1934"; typed copies of correspondence directed to Dr. Parks from Harvey Cushing, J.M.T. Finney, & Hugh Young, commenting on the picture "The All Star Performance," of the first operation performed in the first operating room, under Dr. Halsted, 1937 (a version of the picture is found in the Johns Hopkins Magazine for May, 1976, which is included here); "The Johns Hopkins University School of Medicine, 1893-1943"; "Directory of the Graduates of the School of Medicine of The Johns Hopkins University" 1955; "The Johns Hopkins Hospital seventy-fifth anniversary," 1964; "Dr. Richter, 'Scientific Father', honored," Hopkins Medical News, Nov. 1976; 1977 annual report, The Johns Hopkins Hospital; "The Women's Medical Fund and the opening of The Johns Hopkins School of Medicine," 1979; "William H. Welch," by George J. d'Angele (medical student; presented to the George Corner Society for the History of Medicine, Univ. of Rochester, n.d.); photograph of the team of Hopkins surgeons from "All Star Operation, " 1985 (for an 8 x 10" photo, see Box 8-F36); Hopkins Medical News, 14(1):Summer 1990; "A brief biographical history of the Osler Medical Service, The Johns Hopkins Hospital,"; see also Box 8-F9 pertaining to JAB's class of '34
    - "Osler at Old Blockley", 1940? (Box 11, Folder 3)
      14 x 18" reproduction of a painting by Dean Cornwell, from the "Pioneers of American Medicine" series; a brochure describing the painting and the series, & a flyer with snapshots of the dedication of the Osler Memorial Building, Philadelphia General Hospital
    - Reprints, brochures: history of the UCLA School of Medicine, 1969-1986 (Box 5, Folder 22)
      news story about opening of medical center, Los Angeles Times, June 26, 1955; Inter-national Medical Digest, 85(9), Sep. 1969, featuring a sketch of the UCLA School of Medicine, sent to JAB by John Field; "A drive for a UCLA School of Medicine," The UCLA Alumni Association Occasional Paper, #5:Fall-Winter, 1972-73; certificate of appreciation to Dr. Elmer Belt as "founding grandfather" of the institution, 1975; invitation to Dr. Stafford Leake Warren's 80th birthday celebration, 1976; "Medicine at UCLA," 1980
    - Reprints, brochures: history of the University of Rochester School of Medicine & Dentistry, 1950-1981 (Box 5, Folder 23)
      The Whipple Auditorium Fund Report, & portrait of Dr. Whipple, 1950; 50th anniversary plans for the University of Rochester Medical Center; correspondence with the organizing committee; Rochester Review, Sep. 1955, featuring retirement of George H. Whipple as Dean of the School of Medicine; Medical Review, Univ. of Rochester, Spring 1976, featuring recollections of Dr. Whipple on the occasion of his death; a one-page remembrance by JAB; University of Rochester Medical Review, Summer 1981; photo of Dr. Whipple & William B. Hawkins, [n.d.]; 8x10 photo of Dr. Whipple, [n.d.]; Rochester Medical Alumni News for Dec 1959
    - Reprints, brochures: history of the University of Rochester School of Medicine & Dentistry, 1950-1981 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Class yearbooks of the University of Rochester School of Medicine & Dentistry, 1957-1968 (Box 5, Folder 24)
      "Borborygmi: a chronicle of the Class of 1957"; "The hopefully graduating Class of 1965 presents a short course in Medmanship 1965, or, How to succeed in medical school without really trying"; The Rochester Journal of Medicine, 1(1), May 15, 1967: special issue commemorating the class of 1967; "Merycisms, a game of movement, Class of 1968"
    - Reprints, Lee B. Lusted & Robert S. Ledley, 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 25)
      five reprints on use of computers for medical applications; author inscription
    - Drug data, 1943-1975 (Box 5, Folder 26)
      miscellaneous items
    - "200 years of surgery: milestones in American medicine", 1976 (Box 5, Folder 27)
      brochure produced by Eli Lilly & Co.
    - George H.S. Ramsey & James Sibley Watson, Jr., 1965, 1981 (Box 5, Folder 28)
      newspaper clippings (retirement & obituaries) from the archives of the Univ. of Rochester Edward G. Miner Library
    - Handbook of Physiology, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 29)
      cover letter from H.W. Magoun accompanying the article: "The first American-based Handbook of Physiology" by Frances K. O'Malley and Magoun from The Physiologist, plus photocopies of material from the Handbook
    - "Medical education in the United States," by William H. Welch, 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 30)
      Dr. Welch's article reprinted for the 1985-86 series of Medical Classics, presented by Programs in Medical Classics, Department of Anatomy and Biomedical Library, UCLA Center for the Health Sciences
  - IV. C. MATERIALS ON BOOKS & LIBRARIES
    - "Der Arzt und sein Buch", 1938 (Box 5, Folder 31)
      four pages from an article by Dr. Emil Starkenstein, Philobiblon, 10(7):305-335, 1938, on the library of the Swedish bibliophile, Dr. Erik Waller
    - Three presentations by Robert Vosper1959, 1961, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 32)
      There is no End, Univ. of Minnesota; A Pair of Bibliomanes for Kansas: Ralph Ellis and Thomas Jefferson Fitzpatrick, reprinted from The Papers of the Bibliographical Society of America, 55(3):1961; A Word to the Wise and the Friendly, remarks to the UCLA Friends of the Library
    - Aldous Huxley at UCLA, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 33)
      "A catalogue of the manuscripts in the Aldous Huxley Collection with the texts of three unpublished letters, edited with an introduction by George Wickes." Los Angeles: University of California Library, 1964
    - Nineteenth Century English Fiction, 1964 (Box 5, Folder 34)
      by Gordon N. Ray. Los Angeles: Friends of the UCLA Library, 1964
    - The Elmer Belt Library of Vinciana, 1971-1981 (Box 5, Folder 35)
      Catalogue of the Incunabula in the Elmer Belt Library of Vinciana, by Frances L. Finger. Los Angeles: Friends of the UCLA Library, 1971; excerpts of an interview with Dr. Belt by Willard E. Goodwin for the American Urological Association, focusing on Dr. Belt as urologist, reprinted from Urology, 10(4):Oct. 1977; program for a memorial tribute to Dr. Belt, 1980; brochure about the UCLA Vinciana collection, 1981; 8x10" photos of Dr. Belt [n.d.]
    - John E. Goodwin, Founder of the UCLA Library, 1972 (Box 5, Folder 36)
      "an essay toward a biography," by Lawrence Clark Powell. Los Angeles: Friends of the UCLA Library, 1972
    - "...A Rare Privilege, This, of Being an American", 1974 (Box 5, Folder 37)
      brochure issued by the Friends of the UCLA Library on the occasion of an exhibition of the Gertrude Stein Collection, which was presented to UCLA by Gilbert A. Harrison
    - Sesquicentennial commemorative brochure, National Library of Medicine, 1986, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 38)
      two pamphlets: "The National Library of Medicine and The Friends of the National Library of Medicine celebrate the 150th anniversary of the Library and pay tribute to America's Nobel laureates in medicine, physiology and chemistry," 1986; and, "America's Nobel laureates in medicine, physiology and chemistry: a tribute to America's living Nobel Prize winners," by Larry Thompson. 2nd ed. Summer, 1988
    - Reprints, brochures, etc.: history of books and libraries, 1945-1975 (Box 5, Folder 39)
      by various authors; includes two reprints by Dorothy M. Schullian, 1945, 1947, and two by Martha Teach Gnudi, 1964, 1975
    - Reprints, brochures, etc.: history-of-medicine libraries, 1954, 1957 1961, 1987, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 40)
      The Edward G. Miner Library, University of Rochester; The Wellcome Historical Medical Library; The Trent Collection, Duke University; holiday greetings from the Clendening Medical Library, Univ. of Kansas; "From Hammurabi to Gesell; an exhibit of books (from the Josiah C. Trent Collection...)..., 1961"; "The National Library of Medicine, evolution of a premier information center," JAMA, 1971
    - "An Oliver Twist Exhibition", 1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      subtitle: "A memento for the Dickens Centennial," by Richard A. Vogler. Los Angeles: UCLA University Research Library, 1970
    - "The Codex Hammer by Leonardo da Vinci", 1981 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      brochure describing the provenance & contents of da Vinci's "Codex," acquired by Hammer in 1980
  - IV. D. MISCELLANEOUS MATERIALS
    - List of books transferred from these papers to The John A. Benjamin Collection of Medical History, [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 3)
      ten volumes included in the gift of JAB's papers have been transferred to the Benjamin book collection and are listed in the UCLA library catalogs; those volumes are:
      A guide for authors; manuscript, proof, and illustration, by Payne E.L. Thomas. Springfield, IL: Charles C Thomas, [1949,1958] 85 pp.
      A log house was home: South Dakota stories for my two boys, by T. F. Riggs. First ed. New York: Exposition Press, [c1961]. 208 pp.
      Caesar's commentaries; the Gallic War, Books I-IV, with selections from Books V-VII and from the Civil War, with an introduction, notes, a companion and a vocabulary, by Francis W. Kelsey. Boston: Allyn and Bacon, [c1918] 674 pp. plus 138 pp.
      Fighting in Africa: England's battles with the Boers in the Transvaal, by J. W. Buel. New York: Official Pub. Co., [c1887] 492 pp. Inscribed: "To John from Uncle Raymond, Dec. 20, 1918"
      Handbook of anatomy, being a complete compend of anatomy, by James K. Young. 6th rev. edition. Philadelphia: F.A. Davis Co., 1928. 438 pp. (in addition to JAB's signature, bears signature of Norman L. Cutter, Johns Hopkins, 1929)
      Heroes of the Dark Continent. Title page, pages 1-22, 539-? are missing. Volume is heavily illustrated
      Incunabula in American libraries; a third census of fifteenth- century books recorded by North American collections, compiled & edited by Frederick R. Goff. New York: The Bibliographical Society of America, 1964. 798 pp.
      Laws (abstract) and Board rulings regulating the practice of medicine in the United States and elsewhere. 41st ed., revised Jan 15, 1931. Chicago: American Medical Assoc., 1931. 279 pp.
      Medical writing: the technic and the art, by Morris Fishbein. Chicago: American Medical Association, 1938. 212 pp. (bears stamp inside cover: "Property of Elmer Belt...")
      The saltatorial rodent Dipodomys: the functional and compara- tive anatomy of its muscular and osseous systems, by A. Brazier Howell. Proceedings of the American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 67(10):Dec. 1932.
    - Perspectives in Urology, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      the official American Urological Association History of Urology, Volume 1, 1976; includes JAB's chapter on "Urological x-ray cinematography"
    - Serial issues among JAB's papers, 1934-1982 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      photocopies of the title pages and, where there were annotations by JAB, of the pages noted; 24 titles, 42 items; (the original issues were discarded by the processor)
    - Residencia, 1933 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      subtitle: "Revista de la Residencia de Estudiantes"; serial issue no. 6, Madrid, 1933
    - Essays, 1947-1992 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      "Sherrington's 'Endeavour of Jean Fernel' and 'Man on his Nature'," comments by Gösta Ekehorn, 1947; "Captain James Cook & his voyages of discovery in the Pacific," by Norman J.W. Thrower, 1970; "The history of science collections, Cornell University Libraries," by Dorothy M. Schullian, with a cover letter from Schullian, 1973; "The life and the death of Primo Levi," by John Romano, Mancini Lecture, Nazareth College, Nov. 19, 1992, with letter from Dr. Romano to Mae and John Benjamin; "Bradford Booth & the Saddleir Collection: Three Dedicatory Essays," 1973, by G.B. Tennyson, Bradford A. Booth & Lionel Stevenson, reprinted by the Friends of the UCLA Library from Nineteenth-Century Fiction, 27(4), March 1973
    - "Biological investigations with radioactive calcium & strontium", 1942 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      subtitle: "Preliminary report on the use of radioactive strontium in the treatment of metastatic bone cancer," by Charles Pecher. University of California Publications in Pharmacology, 2(11):117-150, 1942
    - Reprints, miscellaneous subjects, 1941-1982 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      by various authors, including Bennet M. Allen
    - Text for slides, [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 10)
      text from Ecclesiastes, 1,10: "Is there anything whereof it may be said, see, this is new? It hath been already of old time, which was before us"; texts from Milton's Areopagitica; others
    - George Eastman, Picture Story of an Out-of-doors Man, [n.d.] (Box 6, Folder 11)
      hard-cover volume compiled by George Whipple, with the author's signature
    - Third Harrison Howe Lecture, 1947 (Box 6, Folder 12)
      presented at the Rochester Section, American Chemical Society, by Carl F. and Gerty T. Cori, Nov. 17, 1947; program, and 5 x 7" portrait of the Coris in their laboratory
    - University of Rochester, 1950, 1954 (Box 6, Folder 13)
      "The University of Rochester: the first hundred years, 1850-1950"; Rochester Review, 16(1):Sep. 1954, has several features on George Eastman
    - Items relating to UCLA, 1937-1988 (Box 6, Folder 14)
      California of the Southland: A History of the University of California at Los Angeles. Los Angeles: The University of California at Los Angeles Alumni Association, 1937; The UCLA Magazine, May 1944; one issue of The UCLA Alumni Magazine, 1963; National Committee of Sponsors, UCLA Memorial Activities Center, 1963; Report of the University Librarian to the Chancellor, 1969/70-1970/71; The UCLA Alumni Association Occasional Paper, nos. 3 & 4, 1971-1972; UCLA Librarian, issues for: 29(6), Jun. 1976 (includes Martha Teach Gnudi's obituary); 38(1):Jan. 1985; 38(3):Mar. 1985; 41(1):Apr. 1988
    - Items relating to The Johns Hopkins University, 1984 (Box 6, Folder 15)
      Johns Hopkins Magazine, 36(6):Dec. 1984
- V. THE JOHN A. BENJAMIN COLLECTION OF MEDICAL HISTORY
  - V. A. GENERAL MATERIALS
    - Library of JAB, 1940's? (Box 6, Folder 16)
      various handwritten and typed lists of books, some headed "Library of Dr. J.A. Benjamin," but none dated; one page has handwritten note, "Insured items in 1949"; another page is headed, "Library of John A Benjamin - Portraits," with 8 entries
    - Evaluation of the Benjamin Collection of Medical History, 1962-1969 (Box 6, Folder 17)
      correspondence with Henry & Ida Schuman, Robert F. Metzdorf, Martha T. Gnudi; lists of Benjamin books, some with evaluation prices; list of 138 items, a few with prices, headed "Books given as gifts to UCLA Medical Library, July, 1968"
    - Correspondence regarding bequest of the collection to UCLA, 1962-1963 (Box 6, Folder 18)
      content covers the bequest, the shipping & housing of the collection, additions to the original bequest, and also the establishment of a Henry Schuman Lecture in the History of Medicine at the UCLA School of Medicine, supported by JAB; correspondents include JAB; Bennet M. Allen; Elmer Belt; Howard Bern; Louise Darling; John D. French; George H. Hawks, Jr. (attorney); Douglas K. Kinsey (UCLA gifts officer); Clark Kerr; Franklin D. Murphy; C.D. O'Malley; Lawrence C. Powell; Ida (Mrs. Henry) Schuman; Robert Vosper; Stafford Warren
    - Correspondence with UCLA, cont'd., 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      additional contents concern plans for JAB address to UCLA Friends of the Library - see Box 4-F19; additional correspondents added to those listed above: Martha Teach Gnudi; Sherman M. Mellinkoff; Everett T. Moore
    - Correspondence with UCLA, cont'd., 1966-1969 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      additional correspondents: Julia Hawk; Charles J. Hitch; Ralph R. Landes; Robert Moes; Frances Keddie O'Malley; Charles E. Young
    - Correspondence with UCLA, cont'd., 1970-1993 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      some letters from Mae Benjamin; additional correspondents: M. Arndt; A. Bloom; A. Bunting; T. Chew; S. Colville-Stewart; K. Donahue; V. Steele; P. Walter; G. Werner
    - Manuscripts in the Benjamin Collection, 1949,1959 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      descriptions & correspondence to support two projects:
      1) with Prof. C.U. Faye concerning his work on a supplement to the De Ricci Census of Manuscripts, with descriptions of three Benjamin manuscripts, 1949
      2) with Prof. L.C. MacKinney concerning his survey of medieval medical miniatures in America, with descriptions of nine items, and six negatives of Benjamin manuscript #7
    - Later additions to the Benjamin Collection, 1963-1967 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      various gift book lists made by UCLA Biomedical Library staff
    - Catalogs of The John A. Benjamin Collection of Medical History, 1964-1973 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      correspondence re. catalog requests, financing, and typed text for reprint of second supplement
    - Catalogs of The John A. Benjamin Collection of Medical History, 1964, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      MTG's working copies, with annotations, notes, lists, and dealers' descriptions
    - Bookplate for The John A. Benjamin Collection of Medical History, UCLA Biomedical Library, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 27)
      bookplate for the collection; negative and photo of an earlier version of the bookplate
    - The John A. Benjamin Collection of Medical History, UCLA Biomedical Library, 1963-1972 (Box 6, Folder 28)
      descriptions, references, exhibits: "A tribute to Bennet Mills Allen," by JAB, UCLA Librarian, 16(23):180, Sep. 20, 1963; UCLA Health Sciences News Letter, 11(1):Sep. 27, 1963; UCLA Librarian, 17(5):39, Jan. 17, 1964; UCLA Librarian, 17(11):83, Apr. 10, 1964; brochure, "An Exhibit of Rare Books in the History of Urology from the John A. Benjamin Collection of Medical History," mounted for a meeting of the Clinical Society of Genito-Urinary Surgeons, UCLA, Feb. 25- 26, 1965, with photographs of the exhibit and photocopied pages of the Guest Book; also, "Biomedical Library exhibit on the history of urology," UCLA Librarian 18(4):39, Mar. 1965 (for correspondence, see Box 6-F19); "Additional rare books are presented to the Benjamin Collection of Medical History," UCLA Librarian, 18(5):49- 50, Apr. 1965; News Bulletin, Friends of the UCLA Library, no. 6, Feb. 1966; "More rare books for the Benjamin Collection," UCLA Librarian, 19(5):39, May 1966; "Early Spanish imprint added to the medical history collection," UCLA Librarian, 19(10):89, Oct. 1966; "UCLA Library publications in print," UCLA Librarian, 19(11):97, Nov. 1966; "Biomedical Library inaugurates its Rare Book Room," UCLA Librarian, 21(3):16, Mar. 1968; "Rare books on medical history from Professor O'Malley," UCLA Librarian, 21(9):41-42, Sep. 1968; "Library publications in print," UCLA Librarian, 21(12):63, Dec. 1968; "C.D. O'Malley, 1907-1970," UCLA Librarian, 23(4):24, Apr. 1970; UCLA Librarian, 25(3):11-12, Mar. 1972
    - The John A. Benjamin Collection of Medical History, UCLA Biomedical Library, 1973-1994 (Box 6, Folder 29)
      correspondence with persons interested in the collection; UCLA Librarian, 28(12):53, Dec. 1975, with an announcement about the upcoming Biomedical Library exhibit "A Salute to Donors," which included selections from the Benjamin Collection; UCLA Librarian, 37(9):Oct. 1984; "Bennet M. Allen and the first research in neuroendocrinology at UCLA," BRI Bulletin, 8(4):14-17, Fall 1984, includes mention of JAB and his work, and the Benjamin Collection, as well as a group snapshot including JAB in the early 1930s, with a cover letter from the authors, Frances K. O'Malley & H.W. Magoun; catalog, including Benjamin Collection items, for the 14th Congress of the International Association of Bibliophiles, 1985; UCLA Librarian, 39(4):25-26, Jul. 1986, with pictures of the Benjamins, on the occasion of the addition of an Ugo Benzi incunabulum to the collection, honoring JAB's 80th birthday; UCLA Medicine, Summer 1987, with article on the Biomedical Library history of medicine collection & the Benjamin Collection; photograph from the 1989 donor reception; reprint of a D. Schullian review of a biography of Benzi by Lookwood; UCLA Librarian, 47(1):28-31, Summer/Fall 1994, with article about JAB's bookseller correspondence gift
    - The Index of Medieval Medical Images in North America (IMMI), 1989-1990 (Box 6, Folder 30)
      the publication used the Benjamin Collection as a source for appropriate images; correspondence with Dr. Ynez O'Neill & Katharine Donahue; copies of IMMI 1(2):June 1989 and 2(1):March 1990; see also Box 8-F10
  - V. B. CORRESPONDENCE WITH RARE BOOK DEALERS
    - Dawson's of Pall Mall. London, provenance file, 1945-1967 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - F. Thomas Heller, N.Y. provenance file, 1949-1960 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      73 F. Thomas Heller, N.Y. provenance file 1961-1969
    - F. Thomas Heller, general correspondence, 1948-1976 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Raphael King, London, provenance file, 1944-1955 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Raphael King, London, general correspondence, 1944-1956 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - David Low, London, provenance & general correspondence file, 1945-1947 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Emil Offenbacher, N.Y., provenance file, 1943-1968 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Emil Offenbacher, N.Y., general correspondence, 1943-1969 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      see also Box 5-F15
    - Old Hickory Bookshop, Brinklow, MD, provenance & general correspondence file, 1944-1969 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Herbert Reichner, N.Y., provenance file, 1946-1954 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - Herbert Reichner, N.Y., general correspondence, 1944-1955 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - Henry Schuman, N.Y., provenance file, 1942-1945 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - Henry Schuman, N.Y., provenance file, 1946-1968 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Henry Schuman, N.Y., general correspondence, 1942-1969 (Box 7, Folder 15)
      includes: correspondence, publicity, book lists for Henry Schuman Publishers, especially the series "The Life of Science Library"; papers relating to the growth & demise of Henry Schuman Publishers (JAB was a stockholder); Season's greetings, 1944 - the Vesalian muscle men; "Books in the history of urology", annotated by JAB, 1/10/69
    - E. Weil, London, provenance file, 1943-1964 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - E. Weil, London, general correspondence, 1944-1960 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Zeitlin & Ver Brugge, Los Angeles, provenance file, 1960-1969 (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - Zeitlin & Ver Brugge, Los Angeles, general correspondence, 1965-1968 (Box 7, Folder 19)
      see also letter from JAB to JZ, 3/7/47, Box 4-F17